Now that we’ve examined the errors at the token level, let’s move on and look at
sequences with high losses. For this calculation, we’ll revisit our “unexploded” Data
Frame and calculate the total loss by summing over the loss per token. To do this, let’s
first write a function that helps us display the token sequences with the labels and the
losses:
<b>def</b> get_samples(df):
<b>for</b> _, row <b>in</b> df.iterrows():
labels, preds, tokens, losses = [], [], [], []
<b>for</b> i, mask <b>in</b> enumerate(row["attention_mask"]):
<b>if</b> i <b>not</b> <b>in</b> {0, len(row["attention_mask"])}:
labels.append(row["labels"][i])
preds.append(row["predicted_label"][i])
tokens.append(row["input_tokens"][i])
losses.append(f"{row['loss'][i]:.2f}")
df_tmp = pd.DataFrame({"tokens": tokens, "labels": labels,
"preds": preds, "losses": losses}).T
<b>yield</b> df_tmp
df["total_loss"] = df["loss"].apply(sum)
df_tmp = df.sort_values(by="total_loss", ascending=False).head(3)
<b>for</b> sample <b>in</b> get_samples(df_tmp):
display(sample)
<b>0</b> <b>1</b> <b>2</b> <b>3</b> <b>4</b> <b>...</b> <b>13</b> <b>14</b> <b>15</b> <b>16</b> <b>17</b>
▁'' 8 . ▁Juli ▁'' ... n ischen ▁Gar de </s>
<b>tokens</b>
B-ORG IGN IGN I-ORG I-ORG ... IGN IGN I-ORG IGN IGN
<b>labels</b>
O O O O O ... I-ORG I-ORG I-ORG I-ORG O
<b>preds</b>
<b>losses</b> 7.89 0.00 0.00 6.88 8.05 ... 0.00 0.00 0.01 0.00 0.00
<b>0</b> <b>1</b> <b>2</b> <b>3</b> <b>4</b> <b>...</b> <b>14</b> <b>15</b> <b>16</b> <b>17</b> <b>18</b>
<b>tokens</b> ▁' ▁'' ▁Τ Κ ▁'' ... k ▁'' ▁' ala </s>
<b>labels</b> O O O IGN O ... IGN I-LOC I-LOC IGN IGN
<b>preds</b> O O B-ORG O O ... O O O O O
<b>losses</b> 0.00 0.00 3.59 0.00 0.00 ... 0.00 7.66 7.78 0.00 0.00
<b>0</b> <b>1</b> <b>2</b> <b>3</b> <b>4</b> <b>...</b> <b>10</b> <b>11</b> <b>12</b> <b>13</b> <b>14</b>
<b>tokens</b> ▁United ▁Nations ▁Multi dimensional ▁Integra ... ▁the ▁Central ▁African ▁Republic </s>
<b>labels</b> B-PER I-PER I-PER IGN I-PER ... I-PER I-PER I-PER I-PER IGN
<b>preds</b> B-ORG I-ORG I-ORG I-ORG I-ORG ... I- I-ORG I-ORG I-ORG I-
ORG ORG
<b>losses</b> 6.46 5.59 5.51 0.00 5.11 ... 4.77 5.32 5.10 4.87 0.00